翻译：@隐秀_（seriouszyx）
Now that we've written our first program,
我们已经写完了第一套程序
we can reflect a little bit on what we've learned about the Java language.
稍微思考一下从中学到的 Java 语言知识
So first, Java is an object-oriented language
首先 Java 是一种面向对象的语言
that has very strict requirements about how you write programs.
对如何编写程序有严格的要求
So first off, any .Java file has to contain a class declaration.
首先，任何 Java 文件都要包含类的定义
Well, we'll see later that there are also things like interfaces where that's not 100% true,
其实也不绝对，比如我们以后要提到的接口
but it's mostly true to say that every Java file has to have a class declaration.
但是很大程度上是对的，每个 Java 类都要有一个类的定义
Likewise, any piece of code you write, say, the larger method we wrote, has to be part of a class.
同样，编写的代码必须是类的一部分，比如说 larger 方法
The square root function in Java--
Java 中的平方根函数
it's part of a class called math.
math 类的一部分
And we'll see later that things like global constants,
将会看到像全局变量这样的东西
those, too, are part of a class.
这些也是类的一部分
The other thing we saw is that when you want to run a Java program, we have to give a main method.
另一件事是，运行 Java 程序必须提供 main 方法
This is all the code that's going to run when we actually execute the program,
这是运行程序所需的代码
and we declare it using public static void main string brackets args.
使用 public static void main(String[] args) 来定义
And we'll take apart a little bit in the next lecture and in lab one what all this means.
我们将在下节课和实验1中详细介绍它
But for now, we're just treating it as a big old blob of mysteries syntax.
暂时我们仅将其视为一大堆古老的神秘语法
Now the other thing we observed is that Java is a statically typed language.
还要注意 Java 是静态类型语言
So what that means is that when you declare a variable or a parameter for a function
这意味着当定义函数变量
or even the return type for a method,
或者方法的返回类型时
you have to say what type it is.
必须确定是什么类型
Likewise, expressions have a type.
同样，表达式也有类型
So if I say, string x equals 5 plus 10,
如果写 String x = 5 + 10
that 5 plus 10 has type integer, and therefore, it can't-- the result cannot be put in string x.
5加10的类型是整数，因此结果不能放在字符串 x 中
And those types are permanent.
并且类型是不变的
Now the most important thing about the static typing system is that whenever you try and run,
静态类型系统最重要的一点是，每当你尝试运行
or when you try to compile your programs,
或者尝试编译程序
the compiler checks and make sure that all the types are in agreement.
编译器会检查确保所有类型符合规定
And that ensures that you avoid certain types of errors, like,
这可以避免一些错误
well, you avoid specifically type errors.
比如类型错误
So that's unlike a language like Python where the type checks are performed during execution.
这点与 Python 不同，它在运行期间检查类型
OK, so let's reflect a little bit on static typing,
重新思考静态类型
what we might like about it and what we might not.
它的优缺点都是什么
Ordinarily what I would do--
一般这时候我会...
if we lived in an ideal universe,
正常情况下
I'd ask you questions.
我会问你一些问题
But since you're not in my house, I can't do that.
但我无法提问，因为你不在我家
Or at least I assume you're not in my house.
至少我假设你不在我家
I mean, I guess we can check, but it would be pretty weird if I dragged you out here in front of your own self.
如果我把你拽过来，我们模仿一下，那一定很奇怪
No, looks clear, although this is good.
嗯，家里看起来很不错
Hold on.
等一等
I'm still kind of moving in.
我还要进来一下
I see this here Travel Fox poster.
我看到了 Travel Fox 的海报
I got this many years ago.
这是我很多年前买的
It's signed.
有签名
I don't really know who these guys are, exactly, but you know.
其实我不知道他们是谁
Anyway, where were we? Yeah, static type.
我们说到哪儿了？啊，静态类型
The good parts of static typing.
静态类型的优点
Well, One thing that's good about it is it catches certain types of errors,
一个优点是它能捕获错误的类型
making it easier on the programmer to debug their code.
让程序员更容易调试他们的代码
Another good thing is type errors can never occur.
另一个优点是永远不会发生类型错误
Well, I'll say almost, because they kind of can.
应该是几乎不会发生
We'll see later why.
以后我们会看到原因
But type errors can almost never occur on the user's computer, end user's computer.
在最终用户的计算机上几乎不会发生类型错误
So for example, if you're writing an Android app,
假如你正在编写一款 Android 应用程序
really, there should be no danger of a type error reaching their phone,
用户的手机上不应该有类型错误的风险
because ideally, you're not doing anything that's going to cause type errors.
理想情况下，你不会做任何引起类型错误的事情
Another good thing.
另一个优点
Makes it easier to read and reason about code.
使代码更易于阅读和推断
So by looking at code someone else has written,
查看他人编写的代码
everything's got a type.
每样东西都有一个类型
It makes it easier to understand what's going on,
这让我们更容易理解代码的逻辑
especially when we get to bigger programs.
尤其是当我们遇到更大的项目时
And then finally, code can run more efficiently.
最后一点，代码可以更高效地运行
So for example, no need to do expensive runtime type checks.
比如不需要执行耗时的运行时类型检查
There's other reasons.
还有其他原因
When we talk-- now, this isn't a machine structures course.
这不是体系结构课程
We're not going to talk about memory allocation in any great detail.
我们不会详细讨论内存分配
But if you go on to such courses,
但是如果你之后学习这样的课程
you'll learn about why arrays in statically typed languages can be more efficient.
将了解为什么静态类型语言中的数组可以更高效
But a little beyond the scope of our course.
这有点超纲了
Now, the bad side of static types.
静态类型的缺点
Well, codes have to explicitly-- sorry,
代码必须清晰...
I'll just say code is more verbose.
这样写，代码更冗长
I have to actually write out int and string and whatever else everywhere.
比如我必须写出 int 和 String 之类的东西
And code is less general.
而且代码不那么通用
So if we look at the larger method,
我们看一下 larger 方法
this is a larger method that only works for integers.
这个方法只对整型有效
If I wanted to compare strings or even floating point numbers like I have here, 5.5, and I try running this code,
如果我想要比较字符串或者浮点数，比如改成5.5，运行代码
it yells at me. And it says, "cannot do this conversion."
报错“无法进行这种转换”
I can't take a floating point or a so-called double and turn it into an integer.
不能把浮点数或所谓的双精度数变成整数
That's not allowed, whereas in Python that would be no problem.
这是不允许的，但在 Python 中没有问题
There is a way around this in Java called generics.
Java 有一种称为泛型的方式
And they're a fairly decent solution.
这是个相当不错的方法
They're not as good as the equivalent generics in other languages,
它没有其他语言中的泛型好
but we'll see that there is a way out that makes things not totally hopeless.
但至少是一种解决方法
So that's just a high-level summary of some things we've learned about the Java language.
以上是对 Java 知识的高度总结
So I'll just say what's next.
下一步
So there's a homework zero that you can immediately start working on.
可以马上做作业0
So this will give you a chance, if you've never written Java before, a chance to explore the basics on your own.
如果你以前从未编写过 Java，它将给你机会自己探索
Now, this is not a Java class.
这不是一个 Java 课
So we're not going to sit down and carefully go through each piece of syntax.
我们不会坐下来仔细介绍每一个语法
We're going to expect you to go look at reference materials,
我希望你去看看参考资料
to look at example code out there, and use your prior background knowledge to get up to speed on the basics of Java,
去看看示例代码，并凭借你之前的知识快速了解 Java
because once you learn one language, we expect you to start being able to learn other languages very quickly.
因为一旦你学会了一门语言，学习其他语言就会很容易
Next up, there is also a lab.
接下来还有一个实验
Now, if you're someone actually at Berkeley taking the residential version of the course, like the real-life version,
如果你是伯克利的学生，真实注册这门课的话
you can use the lab machines.
你可以使用实验室的机器
But most people just run the code on their own computers.
但大多数人在自己的计算机上运行代码
So lab 1B explains how to compile and run code on your own machine.
实验1B 解释了如何在你自己的计算机上编译和运行代码
But once you are all set up, either using the lab machines of set up to run code on your own machine,
无论是在你自己还是实验室的电脑上，一旦配置好环境
what lab one does is it tells you how to use our system that lets you download the starter files.
实验1会告诉你如何使用我们的系统来下载起始文件
It'll give you some exercises to do and then finally to submit them.
它会给你一些练习然后提交
If you're someone with no prior Java experience,
如果你以前没有使用 Java 的经验
it would be a really good idea to do homework zero before the lab
最好在实验前做完作业0
just so that you have some sense of what writing Java programs is all about.
只是为了让你对 Java 有一些了解
And then finally, in the next lecture,
最后，在下一节课中
we'll talk a little bit about what public static yada yada actually means
我们会简单谈一下 public static 之类的意义
and go a little deeper into some of the object-oriented features for Java.
并稍微深入了解 Java 的一些面向对象特性
And that'll be basically it for the core of the Java language.
这基本就是 Java 的核心部分
And then from there, we'll start getting into some data structures
然后我们开始了解一些数据结构
and learning Java in the context of something that's important to us in the course.
并在课程中一些重要内容的背景下学习 Java
翻译：@隐秀_（seriouszyx）
See you next time.
拜拜